[plane roars overhead]
[birds chirping]
Watch closely, now.
The size and shape
of the smoke signal
relays your message.
-[cloth fluttering]
-[MINE] Come.
Run.
Help.
-Where are you?
-[exclaims]
Enemy.
[NAGISA] Hey, smoke signals?
What are you thinking?
Put that fire out!
What? Why? This is important.
We need to teach Asa
how to communicate
in case we get separated
from her.
You'll attract attention!
Is this so abnormal?
How do people communicate
with each other down here?
Over long distances?
[NAGISA] Uh...
♪
[NAGISA] We have these things
called "phones."
But mine is no use to us.
Even if I could charge it,
I bet it won't connect
to the network.
[ASA (CHILD)] Mom, what is this?
Something old.
I had it when I first wandered
into Higashi Village.
I looked for a payphone
so I could call for help,
but I couldn't find one.
They used to be
on every street corner.
I guess the world
got a little less convenient
while I was trapped
in the mountains.
Bet my transit card
doesn't work anymore, either.
I should still be able to pay
with cash, though. I hope.
We need to find the police
or some other form
of protection.
But then again,
we haven't put enough distance
between us and the village.
Their agents could be
hiding close by,
waiting for us.
The village
where my son is still...
Mom, Dad, what's the plan?
Aren't we going back
for big brother?
-[NAGISA] Hmm?
-I taught Yuru all that I could.
He knows how to survive.
You must have trust
in his abilities.
[Asa (child) gasps]
What should we do? We saved Asa,
but what if they lock Yuru up
in her cell instead?
Huh?
[MAN 1] Hey, someone's here.
I don't recognize them.
Kimonos? That's kind of weird.
Where are you from?
Hi, we're visiting from Tokyo.
You caught us
in our cosplaying getups.
What's that mean?
Funny story.
We got dressed up
in these period clothes
and came out here
to do a photo shoot.
But then we lost our stuff
in the mountains, so--
-Nagisa.
-Huh?
Remind me.
Violence isn't allowed here,
even if we have
a good reason for it?
[MAN 1] We don't wanna hurt you.
Hand the girl over,
and we'll consider
the matter settled.
[MAN 2] You belong
in Higashi Village.
Asa's here.
Are you sure fighting
is the only option?
Afraid so.
[men grunting]
-[thumping]
-[grunting]
[men groaning]
[NAGISA] Even if I tried
to find somebody
who could take us under
their wing and protect us...
as far as the world's concerned,
I've been lost
in the mountains for years.
It would be all over the news
if I popped up out of nowhere.
People across the globe
would be interested
in our story.
We might as well send a map
to Higashi Village
telling them exactly
where to find Asa.
Where can we go that's safe?
How can we protect
our daughter...
and the son
we had to leave behind?
[♪ opening theme song playing]
DAEMONS OF THE SHADOW REALM
[SHINGO] Well, damn.
The electricity bricked
this stupid piece of crap.
[sighs] This is why
I try to avoid using Raijin
unless I have to.
Say hello to my daemons,
Fujin and Raijin.
Their powers should be obvious.
Fujin here controls the wind,
and Raijin controls lightning.
-Let's play nice, buddy boy.
-[Yuru grunts]
EPISODE 18
FUJIN AND RAIJIN
[MAN 1] Ah, crap.
We lost touch with Shingo!
[MAN 2] Huh? What do you mean?
I think that brat they kidnapped
must've done something
to the boss.
He said he was going
to crush Shingo's windpipe
if we didn't release
the hostages.
It sounded like
somebody was choking,
and then the line went dead.
It's no good. My call
won't go through, either.
[grunts] We've got this.
Send some people
to check on him.
Alert the guys
watching the hostages, also!
♪
[MAN 1] Huh? What's the issue?
[MAN 2 ON PHONE]
Where are you right now?
[MAN 1] Not far from gate two.
[MAN 2] Good.
You're close to Shingo.
Go check on him.
As... as in, now.
We'll be right behind you.
Wait, all you want from me
is to go say hi to the boss?
Where's he at?
Yeah, okay, that's not far.
I'll head over. Mm.
I still don't understand
why this is so important,
though.
That one of Shingo's men?
Sounds like it.
[MAN 1] No way, dude.
The twin brother?
I've heard he's, like,
a feral animal.
What if he gets loose
and comes after me?
Now we're talking.
This guy is going to take us
straight to Yuru.
You two ready to show off?
[PIGEON-TOES] Yes, yes!
That human doesn't have daemons.
He won't notice us.
[MAN 1]
You positive this can't wait?
I just picked up
some dinner and--
[MAN 2] Are you kidding me?
Who do you think paid
for that food, huh?
Right, sorry! I am on my way.
-[Bow-Legs grunting]
-[man grunts]
-[Bow-Legs growling]
-[man groaning]
[MAN 2] You there?
What was that weird noise?
Hello?
It was nothing. My phone
just slipped out of my hand.
[PIGEON-TOES]
And just to confirm...
Where is Shingo, again?
I don't remember, exactly.
[MAN 1] TT Logistics office.
On the second floor.
[PIGEON-TOES]
And could you remind me
where the hostages are, too?
[MAN 1] Of course.
The hostages are in the
Oedo Transport reception room.
Cool. I am out. See you.
Nice job. Why don't we go
and grab Yuru first?
Yes, sir.
Your cute little daemons
are total nightmare fuel.
Who'd have known?
And that means
if the twins ever do something
that you don't like,
you can control 'em
with Mamegarasu.
Let's worry about that later.
Right now, we should focus
on saving the boy.
[Dera grunts]
Yozakura, is something wrong?
[SHINGO] Hm?
[scoffs] We've got company.
[Yuru grunts]
[footsteps]
[footsteps continue]
[Yuru breathes shakily]
Hey, good to see you, boss.
[Shingo grunts]
-Why are you here?
-[MAN 1] Good question.
You weren't answering
your phone, so they sent me here
to make sure
nothing bad happened.
The guys were kind of concerned
that things weren't going
according to plan.
It looks like they were worried
for nothing...
-[grunts]
-[Bow-Legs chirps]
[YURU] Huh?
[DERA] There's Yuru!
And Asuma Kagemori.
Aw, hell. You, too?
[gasps] He's got backup
of his own.
The old guy's daemons
control lightning and wind!
Fujin, go!
[grunting]
[DERA]
That wind slices like a blade.
Raijin, now!
[grunts]
[Yuru gasps]
[growls]
[grunts] What the...
[Dera gasps]
[DERA] He's gone!
Asuma, what did you do?
I took him somewhere safer.
We wouldn't want Yuru
to fall back into enemy hands
when we still have
so much to discuss.
This was the wisest option.
[Shingo grunts]
[DERA] Uh... yeah, so.
If Yuru's gone,
then we've got no business here.
[DERA]
Sorry for crashing the party.
[Shingo grunts]
[SHINGO] Fujin.
[BOTH] Uh...
-[both grunting]
-[PIGEON-TOES] "Bow-Legs!"
[BOW-LEGS] "Pigeon-Toes!"
Are you good down there?
Wait! The hell did he go?
[Dera grunts]
[BANDIT] Damn it, he's gone.
The bastard's too fast.
[Shingo chuckles]
[grunting]
[running footsteps]
[DERA] The daemon's flying
slower this time.
Good. Easier to tail him.
[DERA] Huh?
Do they want me to follow?
[gasps] Whoa-whoa!
-[DERA] Yuru, are you okay?
-Good, you made it.
Sorry, I got zapped
by the lightning back there.
And I wasn't able
to move until now.
[DERA] So, what's your deal?
Wait, it's okay.
You can put the gun down.
This is Yozakura,
Asuma's daemon.
They're sort of an ally...
I guess.
-It's complicated.
-[DERA] Huh?
[YURU] When they first
kidnapped me, we had a talk,
and they explained
the situation.
What is this? A cloud of moths?
[grunting]
[YOZAKURA] Forgive
the rough treatment, young Yuru.
Whoa, it can talk!
[YOZAKURA] If I were to speak,
I would give away
my intelligence.
So instead, I play the part
of the dumb daemon
to lower Hayato Shingo's guard.
Who's Shingo?
[YOZAKURA] Asuma's uncle.
First and foremost,
let me say this.
Asuma is no enemy of yours.
Asuma hates Shingo.
He would gladly kill him
if given the chance.
[Yuru grunts]
[YOZAKURA] Gonzo Kagemori
heard of this incident
and is using it both to
weed out traitors in his clan
and to deal with Shingo.
Asuma leapt at the chance
to take down his uncle.
[YURU] It seems strange
he would want
one of his relations
brought down so badly.
What's the story with Shingo?
[YOZAKURA] It starts
with Asuma's mother, Iori.
Shingo never cared
for his little sister.
From the time she was a child,
he treated her as a burden.
But much to his surprise,
the powerful Kagemori head
fell in love with that "burden."
It caused quite a stir
in the Shingo clan.
[Yuru exhales]
[YOZAKURA] Greedy and grasping,
Hayato used his new in-laws
to expand his wealth.
Thanks to his sister,
his business
had grown far larger.
Yet still, he chose to deny her,
never even so much
as thanking her.
His avarice knows no bounds.
Through the Kagemoris,
he learned of Break and Seal's
existence
and has been making moves
to claim those next.
He is like a moth
drawn to a flame.
Though, Higashi Village
is no different in that respect.
You want me to say sorry?
You're around Shingo
all the time.
Surely you could
lop his head off?
Seems like that would've
saved you a lot of trouble.
[YOZAKURA] Hmm.
When facing Fujin and Raijin,
Asagiri and I
are severely disadvantaged.
Lightning would burn us
and wind would blow us away.
We have no recourse
against them.
Asuma is aware of our weakness,
and so feigns obedience
to Shingo.
He's a kind boy.
For my sake and Asagiri's,
he's had to endure much.
[Yuru grunts]
How can you call
that face "kind?"
He's got one of the
shadiest smiles I've ever seen.
[YOZAKURA] I confess,
I don't know how he came
to wear that scheming grin.
It does him no favors.
DAEMONS OF THE SHADOW REALM
[MAN 1] You're serious?
Yeah, yeah, I got it.
Seems the head
of the Kagemori clan
and Asa showed up.
Huh?
[MAN 1] And it sounds like
no one can get in touch
with the boss anymore.
-And what do we make of that?
-[MAN 1] Thing is...
[MAN 2]
The twin brother did what?
[WOMAN] Shingo was captured?
[MAN 1] He wants us
to release the kids.
[MAN 2] They haven't
found us, right?
[MAN 1] Not as far as we know.
♪
[panting]
[gasps] My other half is nearby.
[BOTH] That's fantastic.
[DANJI (TSUGAI)]
Except they're being held
with a girl from the village.
She said the guards have daemons
and they don't know
how to escape.
[FEMALE DAEMON] Oh, no.
Are they the ones
-who attacked your village?
-[DANJI (TSUGAI)] Mm-hmm.
It sounds like
they're being used
as bargaining chips for Yuru.
[MALE DAEMON] No wonder
we haven't seen her.
Poor thing's trapped over there.
One more thing.
Apparently, both the twins
are nearby as well.
[BOTH] Yuru and the real Asa?
[FEMALE DAEMON]
Then we're in good hands.
We could even ask
the Divine Guardians to help!
[MALE DAEMON] Not to brag,
but I think we're pretty
good friends
after that first meet-up!
I don't know.
I mean, Asa probably
hates my partner.
And would Yuru help...
after what I did to him?
I may have ruined everything
with him for good.
[FEMALE DAEMON]
No reason not to check.
[MALE DAEMON]
You missed it after we parted.
Yuru said he had questions
he wanted to ask you.
[Danji (tsugai) exhales]
[FEMALE DAEMON]
I'm sure he'll come,
even if he's mad.
Maybe, but how are we supposed
to contact him
without all the bad guys
finding us?
♪
We can't really hide.
This place is teeming
with daemons.
Who knows if any of them
are friendly?
We'd be safe
with Left and Right,
but I've got no idea
where they might be.
[daemons sigh]
[sighs]
[gasps]
[YOZAKURA] I must apologize.
I put you both through
quite a bit before explaining.
You got that right.
I still don't see why you had
to leave us in the dark.
Not like we wouldn't
have helped you.
Seems like it's in
our best interests as well.
[YOZAKURA] If I had said
everything earlier,
Shingo would've caught on.
I've limited communication
to protect Asuma,
as he's done for us.
Oh, yeah.
Jin hinted at this
when we had our little chat.
[JIN] I'm caught up now.
The enemy knows
that Yuru is off the mountain
and is trying to get him alone.
Furthermore,
they sent a Daemon Wielder
to Higashi Village
who was strong enough
to kidnap the fake Asa
and one of the children.
We need someone
who matches Shingo's greed
and has a whole slew of daemons?
-Funny.
-Sounds familiar.
Yeah, we've got a guy.
Besides, we were planning
on crushing them,
so this all works out.
[Dera chuckles]
[JIN] On the day of the meeting,
we'll send them.
You can go now, Tadera.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
We're not gonna try
fleshin' out a plan
or anything more detailed?
The longer we stay
chatting here,
the more likely
someone takes notice.
We can improvise the rest
on the spot.
How reassuring.
[JIN] One more thing.
While you're there,
you're likely to run into Asuma.
Pretend like
you're out to get him.
He's not actually
on the enemy's side,
so please refrain
from attacking.
And take these.
It's some photos from Asa.
On her behalf, give them
to Mr. Big Brother.
And that was the whole meeting.
-There's no plan?
-Like you're one to talk.
[YOZAKURA] Shingo has
recently hired a Daemon Wielder
of masterful skill.
We're being particularly
cautious of late
to avoid his notice.
He wields dual katanas,
one long, one short. Be careful.
I know him, the sword pervert.
[YOZAKURA] Ivan Yosano.
Say what now?
[DERA] He was seen on the prowl
at night after women.
[grunts] Then he deserves to die
a thousand times over!
He should disembowel himself!
[DERA] I'm afraid
a crime like that
doesn't get you
the death penalty
in modern-day Japan.
-About this perv--
-[YOZAKURA] Ivan.
[grunts] I may or may not have
seen him come to blows
with Left and Right.
And he may or may not know
something about
your mom and dad.
[Yuru gasps softly]
[DERA] I didn't like how dodgy
he was about it.
I'll bet they're still fighting.
They said they'll bring him
back to you alive.
[YURU] Got it.
Then that means we need
to help them. Let's go.
Sure. Just let me grab my rifle.
Hey, Yozakura,
I don't suppose you could--
[YOZAKURA]
I obey only Asuma's orders.
[DERA] Yeah, of course.
♪
[YURU] Smoke signals.
[DERA] What?
Over there. You see?
Maybe? Hmm.
Just seems like fire.
No way. I know those.
I learned them
back in the village.
When I went to hunt,
Danji and I would use them
to talk.
"Need help."
[grunts]
Danji's asking us to help him.
Before, he said he'd look
for his other half.
So if he really found her...
Gotta make a choice.
The hostages,
or the lead on your parents?
[DANJI (TSUGAI)]
I asked Yuru for help.
[ASA (FAKE)] Big brother?
[DANJI (TSUGAI)]
There's no way to be sure
he'll see the smoke signals.
[ASA (FAKE)] Even if he does,
would he help us?
[DANJI (TSUGAI)] I don't know.
I mean, we did
something terrible to him.
[Azami cries]
[ASA (FAKE)]
Azami, it'll be okay.
Someone's on their way
to save us right now.
-Who is it?
-My brother.
I know him, and there's no way
he'd ever abandon you.
[gasps] Yuru is coming?
[sighs]
♪
If we don't hear anything...
[ASA (FAKE)] I just hope
he's careful coming here.
These people are tough,
and they all have daemons.
This really sucks.
[MAN] What? You're here?
-[crashing]
-[all grunt]
[all grunt]
[whimpering]
[yelling]
-You really came!
-Yuru!
[ASA] I wasn't expecting to see
a Higashi Village smoke signal.
The world below has given up
the practice altogether.
So I thought I'd find
my brother here.
[grunts]
GALAXY'S LOUDEST TONGUE CLICK
-[both trembling]
-[DANJI (TSUGAI)] Sorry.
The scary twin showed up.
[♪ closing theme song playing]
NEXT EPISODE PREVIEW
[ASA] Grab those two.
[DANJI (TSUGAI)] Why wouldn't
you go to them before me?
[YURU] Which arm did you use
to cut down my parents?
The next shot I fire
goes into that one!
EPISODE 19
SWORD AND BOW